時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
센히메의 신랑을 찾는 여행에서 방호 역을 맡은 무사시와 코지로.
Musashi and Kojirō was assigned guard duty in the trip of finding Senhime's husband.
그 센히메를 느닷없이 덮친 건 한조에게 지령을 받은 사천왕 중 하나, 지라이얀.
The one who attacked Senhime out of nowhere was one of the four kings, Jiraiyan, who was assigned duty from Hanzō.
위태로웠던 무사시와 코지로. 그 때, 둘 위기를 구해준 건 센히메의 피리였다.
Musashi and Kojirō were in stake. But then, they were rescued by Senhime's flute.
미녀 오니히메, 나타나오
Beautiful Woman Onihime Appears
맛있소! 할멈, 만두 하나 더 주시오.
So good! Granma, one more dish of dumplings-dasu!
이제 안 돼!
No more!
뭐시라?
What?
접시까지 먹으면 충분하다!
Eating the dish itself should be enough!
코지로는!
What about you?!
난 두 접시다.
I only had two dishes.
나도 두 접시야.
I had only two, too.
무사시, 넌 내 조수다! 조수가 나보다 많이 먹는다니 도대체가 용서할 수 없다!
Musashi! You are my assistant! I cannot forgive my assistant eating more than me!
얼마 나왔을까나?
I wonder how much it costs?
예, 10문입니다.
It's 10 mons.
진짜, 자기만 돈을 가지고 있으니 잘난 척은...
Really, only he has money and he's all puffed up...
그치, 센짱?
Don't you agree, Sen-chan?
오, 좋은 남자!
Hey, a good man!
나, 센이라고 해. 넌?
My name is Sen. What about you?
나는 겐지 히카리노스케.
I am Genji Hikarinosuke.
겐지 히카리노스케! 멋진 이름!
Genji Hikarinosuke! What a good name!
저기저기, 같이 만두 안 먹을래?
Hey, hey, would you like to have dumplings with me?
만두?
Dumplings?
뭐가 이상해?
What's so funny?
미안미안. 바로 제안받아서 기쁘긴 해도 저건 여자나 늙은이가 먹는 것.
Sorry. While I'm happy that you asked me, those are for girls or old people.
저기, 그거 뭐야?
Hey, what's that?
삼현금 몰라?
Don't you know Shamisen?
알긴 해도 등에 매다니.
I know, but I never saw it on back.
멋져!
Awesome!
정말 그렇게 생각해?
Do you really think so?
거짓말은 안해. 나도 이걸 좀 할 줄 알아.
I don't lie. I can play this a little bit.
오, 나, 새로운 음악을 위해 여행하고 있어.
Oh, I was travelling to find a new music.
나도 여행하고 있어!
I'm travelling too!
그럼 같이 갈까?
Then shall we go together?
나, 음악이라는 것은 마음이라고 생각해.
I think music represents spirit.
어, 센짱!
Hey, Sen-chan!
이 여행의 목적을 잊었나!
Did you forget why are we on the trip?
센히메의 신랑을 찾는 것이다. 알겠냐? 우리는 단지 센히메를 위험에서 보호해 드리기만 하면 된다.
It is to find Senhime's husband. Got it? We only have to protect her from danger.
그 때, 에도토피아의 한조는...
Meanwhile, Hanzō in Edotopia was...
제너럴 이에야스, 지금 보여주겠다.
General Ieyasu, I'll show you right now.
천하는 이 어둠의 쇼군, 한조가 가져가겠다.
I, Hanzō, the shadow shogun, will take the world.
그를 위해 이에야스의 손녀 센히메를...
For that, I must do something with Ieyasu's granddaugher, Senhime.
오니히메에게 전달해라. 무사시, 코지로를 쓰러뜨리라고!
Let Onihime know that she will have to take Musashi and Kojirō down!
저런 남자의 뭐가 좋소! 정말 센짱은 알다가도 모르겠소! 안 그렇소, 코지로?
What's so good about such man-dasu?! I totally can't understand Sen-chan-dasu. Don't you agree, Kojirō?
안 그렇소라고 말하는 게 안 들리오?!
Don't you hear that I just asked you don't you agree-dasu?!
사람이 누굴 좋아하든 나하고는 관계없는 일이다.
Whoever she likes, I have nothing to do with that.
그건 그럴지 모르겠어도 역시 마음에 안 드오.
That might be true, but I still don't like him.
아!
Hey!
왜 그러냐, 무사시?
What's up, Musashi?
큰일이오!
We have a problem-dasu!
어, 어이! 무슨 일이오! 정신 차리시오!
H- hey! What's wrong-dasu? Wake up-dasu!
도와줘, 무서워!
Help me! I'm scared!
가, 갑자기 괴물이 나와서...
A- a monster suddenly came out...
자세히 설명해 봐라!
Explain in detail!
미야사토 마을이라고 하는 곳에 츠치구모라는 괴물이 나타나서...
A monster named Tsuchigumo has appeared in Miyasato village...
뭐라? 츠치구모가?
What? Tsuchigumo?
그 츠치구모가 마을 사람들을...
That Tsuchigumo is taking...
마을 사람들을 덮쳐서...
taking villagers...
야마타노오로치...
Yamata no Orochi...
츠치구모...
Tsuchigumo...
신이 다스리던 시대부터 명도 천공환, 천지환을 지키고 있다고 전해지는 괴물입니다.
They are monsters that are told to be protecting the sacred swords named Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru.
그 괴물을 퇴치하면 그 명도가 손에 들어오는 것이오!
So by getting rid of those monsters, I will be able to have those excellent swords!
그 때야말로 무사시 님은 천하제일의 검호가 되겠죠.
When that time comes, Mr. Musashi, you'll become the best of the master swordsmen in the world.
주베 씨, 감사하오!
Thank you so much, Mr. Jūbee-dasu!
나, 힘껏 해 보겠소!
I'll do that with all my might-dasu!
야마타노오로치가 천공환. 츠치구모가 천지환.
Tenkūmaru of Yamata no Orochi. Tenchimaru of Tsuchigumo.
그 천지환을 손에 넣을 수 있소.
I'll be able to get that Tenchimaru-dasu.
이럇!
Here I go!
무사시, 어디 가?
Musashi, where are you going?
츠치구모를 잡으러 가오!
I'm going to get Tsuchigumo!
미야사토 마을은 이쪽이에요!
This way is to Miyasato village!
나, 괴물에 흥미가 있어.
I am interested in monsters.
히카리노스케 씨, 기다려!
Mr. Hikarinosuke, wait for me!
츠치구모는 내가 쓰러뜨리오!
I will take down Tsuchigumo-dasu!
츠치구모를 쓰러뜨리면 천지환을 손에 넣을 수 있다. 그러나 가는 길에 기다리고 있는 것은 어떤 괴물일 것인가?
If he takes Tsuchigumo down, then he'll obtain Tenchimaru. But what kind of monster will be waiting for him?
괜찮아?
Are you alright?
그러고 보니 아까부터 계속 걸어만 왔다. 조금 쉬자.
By the way, we've been walking all over. Let's take a short break.
마을은 곧 나와요. 저, 모두한테 강한 사무라이님들이 츠치구모를 쓰러뜨리러 왔다고 사람들에게 전달하러 갈게요!
The village is nearby. I'll let the villagers know that strong Samurais are here to take down Tsuchigumo!
특히 무사시한테 의지해도 된다고 잘 말해주시오!
Don't forget to emphasize that they can depend on Musashi-dasu!
네!
Yes!
입은 살았네, 무사시도 참.
What a big mouth Musashi has.
넉살 좋은 게 무사시의 좋은 점이니까.
Shamelessness is what Musashi's strong at.
역시 그런가.
Figures.
뭣이오?!
What-dasu?!
마을이 아예 없잖아.
There's no village here.
그 오타마라는 여자아이, 어디에 가 버렸는가...
Where did that Otama go to?
어이! 오타마! 어디에 갔소!
Hey! Otama! Where did you go to-dasu?!
나오시오! 오타마!
Come out! Otama!
설마 뭔가 노리던 건가!
Could it be that she was up to something?!
노려?
Up to something?
그 여자아이, 처음부터 우리를 속일 생각이었던 것인가.
Was that girl planning to deceive us at the first place?
뭐하러?
For what?
우리가 길을 잃고 나면 힘빠진 때에 츠치구모가 덤벼들어...
When we get lost, we'd be tired and that'd be perfect time for Tsuchigumo to...
뭐, 뭐오. 단지 박쥐이오.
W- what the-dasu... It was just a bat...
그런 거에 깜짝 놀라긴!
And you get surprised by that?!
나무에 오르면 뭔가 보이지 않을까 하고 생각했소!
I just thought I might see something when I climb up the tree-dasu!
오타마가 속이다니, 생각할 수도 없소!
I can't even think that Otama has deceived us-dasu!
너 코지로라 했지?
You are Kojirō, right?
너도 좀 의심이 많은 것 같은데!
I think you have too much doubts!
언제 적이 올까밖에 생각하고 있지 않으면 어쩌자는 거야.
Isn't it a big problem if you think only about your enemies incoming?
난...
I was...
아, 빛이 보이오!
I can see the light-dasu!
저기에 빛이 있소!
There is the light-dasu!
집이 있소!
There is a house-dasu!
정말 집이다!
There really is a house!
잘됐소! 이제 밥을 먹을 수 있소!
Yay! I can now have dinner-dasu!
누구 있소?
Anyone?
있소?
네, 네, 곧 나옵니다.
Yes, I'll be there soon.
누구십니까?
Who are you?
여긴 미야사토 마을이오?
Is this place Miyasato village?
미야사토 마을은 단지 산 두개만 넘으면 나와요.
You only have to go over two more mountains from now on.
사, 산을 둘씩이나?!
T- two mountains?!
가는 길이 무너져 흐르고 있으니까 지금 가는 건 무리에요.
Since the path is blocked, it's a bad idea to keep going there now.
그래도 오타마라는 마을의 여자얘가...
But a girl named Otama from that village...
아, 오타마라면 아까 마을에 달려서 돌아갔소.
Oh, Otama ran to the village some time ago.
어?
Huh?
미야사토 마을도 가깝네. 그 아이는 역시 우리를 속인 게 아니야.
Miyasato village isn't far away. That kid didn't deceive us or something.
그래도... 가는 길이 무너져 있는데 오타마는 어떻게 쉽게 오가는 거야?
But... how can Otama go to and come from there when the path is blocked?
그건 자기가 사는 곳이니까 빠르게 바위산을 넘나들 수 있는 거지. 낮이라면 너희들도 갈 수 있어요.
That's because she lives there and thus she can easily climb up and down the rock mountain.
If it was daytime, you could easily do that too.
그럼 내일 아침까지 기다려야 하오...
Then do we have to wait until tomorrow morning-dasu?
황무지이긴 해도 괜찮다면 잠시 쉬어가쇼.
There's nothing much here, but you can stay here if you want to.
우와, 고맙소! 그렇게 해야겠-
Thank you so much! We must do so-
그 김에 밥도...
And we'd like some food too...
야호!
Yay!
반찬 없는 단순한 밥일 뿐이니 밥이라도 가득 드쇼.
There's not much than rice, so please eat rice as much as you can.
정말, 반찬이 아무것도 없는데도 맛있소.
Really, there's nothing at all, but it tastes so good-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
그렇게 말하는 건 실례야!
That is a rude thing to say!
맛있다고 칭찬하는 게 말이오?
Is praising for the good taste bad-dasu?
그게 아니야! 반찬이 아무것도 없다니!
That's not it! It's that you just said there is nothing!
아무것도 없는 건 없는 거니까!
What's not there is not there!
무사시는 타인의 기분이란 걸 생각해 본 적이 있니?
Musashi, have you ever thought about someone else's feelings?
뭐라?!
What?!
마음의 쓰라림이라던가, 슬픔이라던가, 친절함이라던가, 앓는 것이라던가, 동정심이라던가, 측은지심이라던가!
Soreness, sadness, kindness, affliction, sympathy, or compassion!
그 정도는 나도...
I know that!
자, 자, 어려운 이야기는 괜찮으니까 가득 드쇼.
Now, now, stop the difficult conversation and just eat.
이렇게 맛있는 건 난 정말 처음 먹어!
I never had something this good!
배가 고프면 뭐든 맛있게 느껴져요.
When you're hungry, everything tastes so good.
그게 맞소!
That's right!
한 그릇 더!
One more dish!
나도!
Me too!
젊은 것들은 그렇게 해야 말라붙은 놈들보다 통통하게 살쪄있는 게 먹는 맛이 있으니까.
Young kids shouldn't be so slim, since chubby ones do taste better!
먹는 맛이 있어?
Taste better?
자, 다음은 누구냐?
Now, who's next?
아, 나이오!
Oh, that's me-dasu!
할머니.
Grandma.
무사시가 본 것은 대체 무엇인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
What did Musashi just see? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
츠치구모!
Tsuchigumo!
무사시!
Musashi!
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
츠치구모가!
There's Tsuchigumo!
어디에 있어?!
Where is it?!
문 밖에 엄청 큰 그림자를 보였소!
It just showed a huge shadow over the sliding door!
또 공포심에 환영을 본 게...
Shouldn't it just be a illusion made out of fear?
아니, 나도 확실히 방금... 기분나쁜 악기를 느꼈으니.
No, I did just feel an eerie malice.
먹으면 맛있겠지.
It's gonna be tasty when you eat.
칼을 갈고 있소.
She's griding her knife.
어째서...
Why?
설마...
Could it be...
가봐, 무사시! 사무라이잖아?
You go, Musashi! Aren't you a Samurai?
이런 때만은 뺀질거리겠소!
I'd rather be not at a time like this-dasu!
뭔 일이니?
What's up?
하, 할머니, 뭘 하오!
G- grandma, what are you doing-dasu?!
내일 아침 모두에게 메밀국수를 주려고 그래서 말야. 이곳 국수 맛은 보기에는 이래도 같이 먹는 과자가 참 맛있단다.
I was thinking about giving noodles to you people tomorrow morning. The starch noodles are great.
그런 것이었소!
So that was it-dasu!
놀래키지 마, 정말!
Don't make us surprised!
??? 씨가 원하는 음악과는 전혀 다르긴 해도.
Mine is totally different from the music that ??? is looking for.
으응, 그건 그걸로 괜찮아. 잘하잖아, 센짱?
Nah, it's all right. You're good at it anyway, Sen-chan.
정말?
Really?
그래도, 왠지 마음의 집중이 아직 부족한 것 같아.
But I somehow feel that you aren't concentrating with your spirit as much as you can.
마음의 집중?
Concentrating?
뭐든 그렇다 생각하지만, 나, 제일 소중한 것은 기술보다도 마음이라고 생각해.
It's true for everything; I think what's most important is spirit, rather than techniques.
마음.
Spirit.
음악은 특히 그래. 나, 언젠가는, 이 난세를 내 음악으로 평화한 세상으로 만들어 보이고 싶어.
Especially for musics. I want to make this world peaceful with my music in future.
꿈일지도 모르겠지만.
It might be just a dream, though.
그래도 멋진 꿈이야.
But still, it's an awesome dream.
그런 의미로 나, 내 음악이 괴물에게 통할지 아닐지 시험해 보고 싶어.
Just like that, I want to test it out if my music will have effect on monsters or not.
통한다니?
Have effect?
그러니까, 괴물이 내 음악을 듣고 나쁜 짓을 하지 않게 되었으면 좋겠는데.
I mean, I'd like if the monsters stop doing bad things after listening to my music.
그렇게 될 리가 없소!
No way that's happening-dasu!
어쨌든 우리 역할은 여기서 끝날지도 모르지.
Anyway, our duty might end right here.
에? 설마 센짱이 저 음악놈을 신랑으로 한다는 게...
Huh? Are you saying that Sen-chan is going to have that music guy as her husband...?
그럴 가능성도 충분하지.
That's possible.
무슨 말을! 뭐가 뭐래도 센짱이 저런 무예가가 아닌 남자하고...
Impossible! No matter what, Sen-chan wouldn't do that with someone who's not a martial artist!
그러니까말로, 신선한 느낌이기는 하지. 여자란 그런 것이다.
That's why I agree that it's a fresh idea for her. That's how girls are.
어라? 잘 아는 듯이 그러시오.
Huh? You're talking as if you know girls well-dasu.
히카리노스케 씨! 나하고...
Mr. Hikarinosuke! Let's...
아, 설마, 서두르면 안 되오!
Err, no way, you shouldn't decide in hurry-dasu!
나하고 같이 연주하자!
Let's play a music together!
-같이 하자.
-응! 기대되네!
-Let's do it together.
-Yeah! I'm so puffed up!
진짜, 멋대로 기대했소!
Me and my expectations...
할멈, 소바 맛있었소!
Grandma, the noodles were great!
그건 잘 되었구나.
That's good to hear.
덕분에 안내도 해줘서 감사하오!
Moreover, you're guiding us, and we're grateful for that-dasu!
무슨, 이 정도야 일도 아니지.
Nah, this is nothing, really.
왠지 기분나쁜 곳이야.
I have a bad feeling about this place.
저기만 넘으면 미야사토 마을이 보일 거야.
You'll see Miyasato village as soon as you go over there.
정말 심하게 좁은 곳이오.
This passage is really narrow-dasu.
어라? 자, 잠깐!
Huh? W- wait!
아, 히카리노스케, 기다리시오!
Hikarinosuke, wait for me!
무사시, 빨리 가!
Musashi, hurry up!
아니, 그런 말을 해도 머, 머리가...
Uh, even if you say so, my head is...
히카리노스케! 무슨 일이오!
Hikarinosuke! What happened-dasu?!
히카리노스케 씨!
Mr. Hikarinosuke!
센히메...
Senhime...
어지간히 날카로운 것에 당했어.
He was done for with something very sharp.
실이...
A string...
츠치구모의 실이다.
Tsuchigumo's string.
길게 이어져 있어.
It's long.
그 할머니, 설마...
Could that grandma be...
무사시! 조심해라!
Musashi! Be careful!
할머니! 어디 있소!
Grandma! Where are you-dasu?!
살려줘!
Help me!
어제 그 젊은 여자아이의 비명. 그걸 듣고서 가만히 있을 무사시가 아니었다.
The scream of the girl that he saw yesterday. Musashi wouldn't stay put after hearing that.
저건!
That must be...
저건 틀림없이 천지환!
That must be Tenchimaru!
살려줘!
Help me!
오타마!
Otama!
지금 가오!
I'm going right now!
뭐, 뭣이오!
W-what-
츠치구모!
Tsuchigumo!
갑자기 나오다니 비겁하오!
It's cowardly to come out of nowhere-dasu!
코지로!
Kojirō!
이 녀석은 내게 맡겨라. 무사시는 저 아가씨를!
Leave this to me. Musashi, save that girl!
와라, 괴물!
Come attack me, monster!
오타마, 정신 차리시오!
Otama, wake up-dasu!
오타마, 내 등에 타시오!
Otama, get onto my back!
고맙군.
Thank you.
무사시! 저건 오타마가 아니야!
Musashi! She isn't Otama!
죽어라, 무사시!
Die, Musashi!
뭔 짓이오!
What are you doing-dasu?!
각오하시오!
Prepare yourself-dasu!
이런 늙은이를 괴롭힐 겐가?
Are you going to torment an old woman?
할머지...
Grandma...
무사시!
Musashi!
나는 오니히메. 센히메를 가져가겠다!
I am Onihime. I'll take Senhime!
오니히메
Onihime
뭘 위해!
For what?!
죽을 자는 그런 건 몰라도 된다. 무사시와 코지로는 여기가 무덤이라는 걸 아는 걸로 충분하다!
People to be executed don't need to know about that.
Musashi and Kojirō, you should be happy to know that this place will be your grave!
가라, 츠치구모!
Go, Tsuchigumo!
천지환을 빼앗을 셈인가. 그걸 끌어안고 죽어라!
Trying to take Tenchimaru? You'd better die embracing that!
빈틈이다!
Chink in the armor!
센짱!
Sen-chan!
살려줘!
Help me!
벤케이!
Benkei!
이제 안심하쇼!
You can be relieved now!
벤케이!
Benkei!
나는 우시와카. 힘을 모아 퇴치를!
I am Ushiwaka. Let's get rid of them together!
우시와카!
Ushiwaka!
웃기는군. 다 함께 죽여주지!
Feeling lucky? I'll kill you all!
가라! 츠치구모!
Go! Tsuchigumo!
나머지는 맡기오!
I'll leave the rest to you-dasu!
무사시! 조심해라!
Musashi! Be careful!
코테츠가!
My Kotetsu!
히카리노스케와 코테츠의 원수를 갚겠소!
I'll take revenge for Hikarinosuke and Kotetsu-dasu!
천지환. 대단한 검이오.
Tenchimaru. It is an excellent sword-dasu.
아, 아름다워!
B- beautiful!
달아날 셈이오!
Running away-dasu?!
우리도 오니히메와 츠치구모의 소문을 듣고 퇴치하러 왔습니다.
We're here to get rid of Onihime and Tsuchigumo after we heard about them.
그래도 이런 곳에서 만나다니 참!
But still, I didn't expect to meet you here!
이 천지환, 내가 맡아도 괜찮겠소?
Can I keep this Tenchimaruto myself-dasu?
칼 모으는 건 관뒀으니까 가져가시라!
I'm done with collecting swords, so do whatever you want!
히카리노스케 씨, 같이 연주하자는 약속, 지키지 못하게 되었네.
Mr. Hikarinosuke, you couldn't keep the promise of playing the music together.
당신의 음악은 언제까지나 내 마음 속에...
Your music will be always in my heart...
무사시 일행은 우시와카와 벤케이와 재회를 약속하고 갈라져 다시 여행길을 떠났다.
Musashi's group promised to meet Ushiwaka and Benkei again, and they parted and kept going on their journey.
그러나 이 여행이 평온무사할 리가 없다. 다음에 다가올 시련은 무엇인가.
But there is no way this journey is going to be peaceful and safe. What is waiting for him?
어쨌든, 꺾이지 마라, 무사시, 코지로, 센히메! 밝은 희망이 기다리고 있다!
Nonetheless, don't be dispirited, Musashi, Kojirō, and Senhime! Bright future is waiting for you!
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
주베 씨가 말한 요괴 야마타노오로치를 만났소.
I met Yamata no Orochi that Mr. Jūbee told me-dasu.
좋소, 이놈을 잡으면 천공환도 손에 넣고 내 이도류도 천하무적이 되오!
Alright! When I get this thing, I'll have Tenkūmaru in my hands and I'll be invincible-dasu!
다음 카라쿠리 요술사의 이름은 슈텐타이가.
Next Karakuri magician is Shutentiger.
다음 이야기! 야마타노오로치, 대결전이오!
Next story! Yamata no Orochi, a Big Showdown!
질풍노도의 이도류이오!
It's stormy dual blade-dasu!
다음 이야기
야마타노오로치, 대결전이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
A Big Showdown Against
Yamata no Orochi
Look forwards for it!